<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<elements>
    <info>
        <name></name>
        <update version="1.5.0">
            <file name="psion-expandedoptions.xml" url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/Zenoverlordian/Aurora-Builder-KibblesTasty/main/psion-expandedoptions.xml" />
        </update>
    </info>
    <!--Version 1.4-->
    <!--DISCIPLINES-->

    <!--SUBCLASSES-->

    <!--SPELLS-->
    
    <element name="Inner World" type="Spell" source="KibblesTasty Psion" id="ID_KIBBLESTASTY_PSION_SPELL_INNER_WORLD">
        <supports>Psion_KTH</supports>
        <description>
            <p>As an action, you create and enter an imaginary world. All other creatures within 120 feet are pulled this world with you. This world is centered on you, and extends in 120 feet in all directions.</p>
            <p class="indent">A creature that reaches the edge of this world can make a Charisma saving throw to attempt to exit, spending 5 feet of movement to return where they were before being pulled into the world on success, and being unable to move out the world until the start of their next turn on failure. A creature outside the world can attempt to enter it by moving to where you cast the spell (which is marked by a glowing psionic rift) and making a Charisma saving throw to enter the world. You can allow a creature to automatically pass their save to enter or exit the world.</p>
            <p class="indent">When you create this world, you can create obstacles and terrain of your choice, creating walls, pillars, and other obstacles that take up to twenty 5 by 5 square foot areas (stylistically, these can appear however you choose). These can be placed consecutive or spread out in any method of your choosing, but any area with a creature must contain an path that creature can fit through to both you and the edge of the of the world.</p>
            <p class="indent">You can additionally create up to five hazardous spaces on the ground that are 5 foot squares. These can be fires, spikes, biting mouthes, or whatever you choose, but regardless of its form if a creature takes 4d4 + 4 psychic damage when it enters the effect's area for the first time on a turn or starts its turn there. Each of these hazards must be at least 20 feet from another hazard.</p>
            <p class="indent">While in this inner world, if you fail saving throw, you choose to succeed instead. You can do up to 3 times during the duration of the spell. All spells and powers have their psi point cost reduced by one.</p>
            <p class="indent">During the spell, as an action, you can cause attempt to destroy a creature within the world. The target must make an Intelligence saving throw. On failure, it takes 8d8 + 8 psychic damage and is removed from the imaginary world, returning to where they were before being pulled into it.</p>
            <p class="indent">The world can be bright or dim light, and you control the weather within it.</p>
            <p class="indent">When the spell ends, you and any creature that remains in the world exit the world returning to space you entered the world from.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords"></set>
            <set name="level">8</set>
            <set name="school">Psionic</set>
            <set name="time">1 action</set>
            <set name="range">Self</set>
            <set name="duration">Concentration, Up to 1 minute.</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">false</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
            <set name="materialComponent" />
            <set name="isConcentration">true</set>
            <set name="isRitual">false</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    
    <!--TALENTS-->

    <element name="Master of Stolen Power" type="Class Feature" source="KibblesTasty Psion" id="ID_KIBBLESTASTY_PSION_TALENT_MASTER_OF_STOLEN_POWER">
        <supports>Psionic Talent</supports>
        <prerequisite>Consumption Discipline, 15th level Psion</prerequisite>
        <requirements>ID_KIBBLESTASTY_PSION_DISCIPLINE_CONSUMPTION,[level:psion:15]</requirements>
        <description>
            <p><em>Prerequisite: Consumption Discipline, 15th level Psion</em></p>
            <p>While you are in a boosted state from Mind Leech (with an additional 1d6 damage to add to psionic power), you gain an additional psi point from Psionic Mastery.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>While you are in a boosted state from Mind Leech (with an additional 1d6 damage to add to psionic power), you gain an additional psi point from Psionic Mastery.</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>
    <element name="Mind Feast" type="Class Feature" source="KibblesTasty Psion" id="ID_KIBBLESTASTY_PSION_TALENT_MIND_FEAST">
        <supports>Psionic Talent</supports>
        <prerequisite>Consuming Mind Subclass, 9th level Psion</prerequisite>
        <requirements>ID_KIBBLESTASTY_PSION_ARCHETYPE_CONSUMING,[level:psion:9]</requirements>
        <description>
            <p><em>Prerequisite: Consuming Mind Subclass, 9th level Psion</em></p>
            <p>You can gain further nourishment by literally consuming the minds of your fallen foes, adapting your metabolism. If you take a short or long rest while having access to the corpse of a fallen foe that died in the last hour and that had an Intelligence of 8 or higher, you can consume part of their mind, gaining extra psi points over your normal limit equal to the creature's CR (up to your proficiency bonus).</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>If you take a short or long rest while having access to the corpse of a fallen foe that died in the last hour and that had an Intelligence of 8 or higher, you can consume part of their mind, gaining extra psi points over your normal limit equal to the creature's CR (up to {{proficiency}}).</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>
    <element name="Mind Thief" type="Class Feature" source="KibblesTasty Psion" id="ID_KIBBLESTASTY_PSION_TALENT_MIND_THIEF">
        <supports>Psionic Talent</supports>
        <prerequisite>Consumption Discipline</prerequisite>
        <requirements>ID_KIBBLESTASTY_PSION_DISCIPLINE_CONSUMPTION</requirements>
        <description>
            <p><em>Prerequisite: Consumption Discipline</em></p>
            <p>You can gain an additional number of skill, tool, or language proficiencies from Adaptive Hunter equal to half your proficiency bonus (rounded down) before losing the previously gained proficiency. If you would gain an additional proficiency from it beyond that, the first one you gained is lost.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>You can gain an additional {{proficiency:half}} skill, tool, or language proficiencies from Adaptive Hunter before losing the previously gained proficiency. If you would gain an additional proficiency from it beyond that, the first one you gained is lost.</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>
    <element name="Tranquil Meditation" type="Class Feature" source="KibblesTasty Psion" id="ID_KIBBLESTASTY_PSION_TRANQUIL_MEDITATION">
        <supports>Psionic Talent</supports>
        <prerequisite>Enhancement Discipline</prerequisite>
        <requirements>ID_KIBBLESTASTY_PSION_DISCIPLINE_ENHANCEMENT</requirements>
        <description>
            <p><em>Prerequisite: Enhancement Discipline</em></p>
            <p>When you take a short rest and expend hit dice, both you and any allied creatures that takes a short rest within 60 feet of you regains additional hit points equal to the number of hit dice you expend + your intelligence modifier.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>When you take a short rest and expend hit dice, both you and any allied creatures that takes a short rest within 60 feet of you regains additional hit points equal to the number of hit dice you expend + {{intelligence:modifier}}.</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>
    <element name="Vampiric Strength" type="Class Feature" source="KibblesTasty Psion" id="ID_KIBBLESTASTY_PSION_TALENT_VAMPIRIC_STRENGTH">
        <supports>Psionic Talent</supports>
        <prerequisite>Consuming Mind Subclass</prerequisite>
        <requirements>ID_KIBBLESTASTY_PSION_ARCHETYPE_CONSUMING</requirements>
        <description>
            <p><em>Prerequisite: Consuming Mind Subclass</em></p>
            <p>A creature that is grappled by you has disadvantage on saving throws against your Mind Leech psionic power.</p>
            <p class="indent">Additionally, a creature that fails its saving throw against Mind Leech has disadvantage on Strength (Athletics) and Dexterity (Acrobatics) checks to contest grapples against you until the start of your next turn.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>A creature that is grappled by you has disadvantage on saving throws against your Mind Leech psionic power. Additionally, a creature that fails its saving throw against Mind Leech has disadvantage on Strength (Athletics) and Dexterity (Acrobatics) checks to contest grapples against you until the start of your next turn.</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>

    <!--FEATS-->

    <element name="Psionic Synthesis" type="Feat" source="KibblesTasty Psion" id="ID_KIBBLESTASTY_PSION_FEAT_PSIONIC_SYNTHESIS">
        <prerequisite>4th level Psion</prerequisite>
        <requirements>[level:psion:4]</requirements>
        <description>
            <p>You gain the ability to meld your Psionic abilities together to produce potent new effects. When you select this feat, you can select one Fusion talent for free. You can only select fusion talents when you have all the Disciplines in their prerequisite.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>You gain the ability to meld your Psionic abilities together to produce potent new effects. When you select this feat, you can select one Fusion talent for free.</description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <select type="Class Feature" name="Psionic Synthesis" supports="Psionic Talent, PsionicSynthesis" />
        </rules>
    </element>

    <!--Synthesis Talents-->

    <element name="Enhanced Constructs" type="Class Feature" source="KibblesTasty Psion" id="ID_KIBBLESTASTY_PSION_TALENT_ENHANCED_CONSTRUCTS">
        <supports>Psionic Talent, PsionicSynthesis</supports>
        <prerequisite>Psionic Synthesis, Enhancement Discipline, Projection Discipline</prerequisite>
        <requirements>ID_KIBBLESTASTY_PSION_DISCIPLINE_ENHANCEMENT, ID_KIBBLESTASTY_PSION_FEAT_PSIONIC_SYNTHESIS, ID_KIBBLESTASTY_PSION_DISCIPLINE_PROJECTION</requirements>
        <description>
            <p>Your Astral Construct can be affected by Enhancing Surge, and for the purposes of Talents, is considered you, though you must choose if you or it receive the benefits. Additionally, you can consider your Astral Construct a creature for the purposes of Enhancement Alternate Effects in the following ways:</p>
            <ul>
                <li>Any time it gains hit points or temporary hit points, it becomes Solidified and gains those hit points until they are depleted; it can have a maximum hit points equal to your Psion level.</li>
                <li>Increased Movement Speed increases the distance you can move it, including movement gained from the Dash action.</li>
                <li>Any additional actions it gains, it can take during your turn at your direction (no action required).</li>
            </ul>
            <p class="indent">Additionally, when you use an Enhancing Surge or Alternate Effect, you can double the psi points spend to make it affect both you and your Astral Construct (you cannot exceed your normal psi point limit doing this).</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>Your Astral Construct can be affected by Enhancing Surge, and for the purposes of Talents, is considered you, though you must choose if you or it receive the benefits. When you use an Enhancing Surge or Alternate Effect, you can double the psi points spend to make it affect both you and your Astral Construct (you cannot exceed your normal psi point limit doing this). Additionally, you can consider your Astral Construct a creature for the purposes of Enhancement Alternate Effects in the following ways:
            Any time it gains hit points or temporary hit points, it becomes Solidified and gains those hit points until they are depleted; it can have a maximum of {{level:psion}} hit points.
            Increased Movement Speed increases the distance you can move it, including movement gained from the Dash action.
            Any additional actions it gains, it can take during your turn at your direction (no action required).</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>

    <element name="Elemental Phasing" type="Class Feature" source="KibblesTasty Psion" id="ID_KIBBLESTASTY_PSION_TALENT_ELEMENTAL_PHASING">
        <supports>Psionic Talent, PsionicSynthesis</supports>
        <prerequisite>Psionic Synthesis, Psychokinetics Discipline, Transposition Discipline</prerequisite>
        <requirements>ID_KIBBLESTASTY_PSION_FEAT_PSIONIC_SYNTHESIS, ID_KIBBLESTASTY_PSION_DISCIPLINE_PSYCHOKINETICS, ID_KIBBLESTASTY_PSION_DISCIPLINE_TRANSPOSITION</requirements>
        <description>
            <p>As you step between planes, you can tap into the Elemental Planes, bringing their power into the material with you. You can use Psychokinetic modifiers on Phase Rift (excluding Massive).</p>
            <p class="indent">Additionally, whenever you deal damage to an area with a Psychokinetics ability that would include yourself, you can phase yourself out of reality taking no damage from the effect.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>You can use Psychokinetic modifiers on Phase Rift (excluding Massive). Additionally, whenever you deal damage to an area with a Psychokinetics ability that would include yourself, you can phase yourself out of reality taking no damage from the effect.</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>

    <element name="Kinetic Mastery" type="Class Feature" source="KibblesTasty Psion" id="ID_KIBBLESTASTY_PSION_TALENT_KINETIC_MASTERY">
        <supports>Psionic Talent, PsionicSynthesis</supports>
        <prerequisite>Psionic Synthesis, Psychokinetics Discipline, Telekinetics Discipline</prerequisite>
        <requirements>ID_KIBBLESTASTY_PSION_FEAT_PSIONIC_SYNTHESIS, ID_KIBBLESTASTY_PSION_DISCIPLINE_PSYCHOKINETICS, ID_KIBBLESTASTY_PSION_DISCIPLINE_TELEKINESIS</requirements>
        <description>
            <p>Your ability to manipulate energy becomes a single blended prowess, freely swapping between manipulating force and energy. You can apply Telekinetic Force modifiers to Kinetic Blast and Elemental Blast modifiers to Telekinetic Force (though to do not gain any benefits from from a Specialization while doing so).</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>You can apply Telekinetic Force modifiers to Kinetic Blast and Elemental Blast modifiers to Telekinetic Force (though to do not gain any benefits from from a Specialization while doing so).</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>

    <element name="Physical Telekinesis" type="Class Feature" source="KibblesTasty Psion" id="ID_KIBBLESTASTY_PSION_TALENT_PHYSICAL_TELEKINESIS">
        <supports>Psionic Talent, PsionicSynthesis</supports>
        <prerequisite>Psionic Synthesis, Enhancement Discipline, Telekinetics Discipline</prerequisite>
        <requirements>ID_KIBBLESTASTY_PSION_FEAT_PSIONIC_SYNTHESIS, ID_KIBBLESTASTY_PSION_DISCIPLINE_ENHANCEMENT, ID_KIBBLESTASTY_PSION_DISCIPLINE_TELEKINESIS</requirements>
        <description>
            <p>When you use a Enhancing Surge to empower a creature, you can expend a psi point augment it with your Telekinesis to further assist them, optionally granting one of the following benefits:</p>
            <ul>
                <li>You can move the creature 10 feet (this movement does not provoke opportunity attacks).</li>
                <li>You can telekinetically deflect the first weapon attack against them before the start of your next turn, giving that attack disadvantage.</li>
                <li>You can telekinetically boost their next athletics check or weapon attack before the start of your next turn, granting that check or attack advantage.</li>
            </ul>
            <p class="indent">Addititionally, while under the effect of Enhancing Surge, the amount you can lift, drag, or carry is doubled with assistance of your telekinesis, and you can apply Telekinetic Force modifiers to your weapon attacks.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>While under the effect of Enhancing Surge, the amount you can lift, drag, or carry is doubled with assistance of your telekinesis, and you can apply Telekinetic Force modifiers to your weapon attacks.Additionally, when you use a Enhancing Surge to empower a creature, you can expend a psi point augment it with your Telekinesis to further assist them, optionally granting one of the following benefits:
            You can move the creature 10 feet (this movement does not provoke opportunity attacks).
            You can telekinetically deflect the first weapon attack against them before the start of your next turn, giving that attack disadvantage.
            You can telekinetically boost their next athletics check or weapon attack before the start of your next turn, granting that check or attack advantage.</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>

    <element name="Planar Projections" type="Class Feature" source="KibblesTasty Psion" id="ID_KIBBLESTASTY_PSION_TALENT_PLANAR_PROJECTIONS">
        <supports>Psionic Talent, PsionicSynthesis</supports>
        <prerequisite>Psionic Synthesis, Projection Discipline, Transposition Discipline</prerequisite>
        <requirements>ID_KIBBLESTASTY_PSION_FEAT_PSIONIC_SYNTHESIS, ID_KIBBLESTASTY_PSION_DISCIPLINE_PROJECTION, ID_KIBBLESTASTY_PSION_DISCIPLINE_TRANSPOSITION</requirements>
        <description>
            <p>You gain the ability to project beings from other planes into partial reality as magical constructs. You learn the following spells and cast them as Alternate Effects of Projection, expending psi points as shown on the table below to cast them using your Psionics feature. You can cast them at higher levels be expending additional psi points.</p>
            <p class="indent">Unlike other spells cast by the Psionics feature, you need either material component of the spell, or a psionic crystal worth at least 100 gp x the number of psi points spent to cast the spell as the material component; the material component is not consumed by the casting of the spell. Additionally, any of the following spells that you are concentrating ends if you complete a short or long rest.</p>
            <table>
                <thead>
                    <tr><td>Psi Points</td><td>Alterante Effect</td></tr>
                </thead>
                <tr><td>2</td><td>summon beast</td></tr>
                <tr><td>3</td><td>summon fey</td></tr>
                <tr><td>4</td><td>summon elemental</td></tr>
                <tr><td>5</td><td>summon aberration</td></tr>
                <tr><td>5</td><td>summon celestial</td></tr>
                <tr><td>6</td><td>summon fiend</td></tr>
            </table>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>Unlike other spells cast by the Psionics feature, you need either material component of the spell, or a psionic crystal worth at least 100 gp x the number of psi points spent to cast the spell as the material component; the material component is not consumed by the casting of the spell. Additionally, any of the following spells that you are concentrating ends if you complete a short or long rest.</description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <grant type="Spell" spellcasting="Psion_KTH" id="ID_WOTC_TCOE_SPELL_SUMMON_BEAST" />
            <grant type="Spell" spellcasting="Psion_KTH" id="ID_WOTC_TCOE_SPELL_SUMMON_FEY" />
            <grant type="Spell" spellcasting="Psion_KTH" id="ID_WOTC_TCOE_SPELL_SUMMON_ELEMENTAL" />
            <grant type="Spell" spellcasting="Psion_KTH" id="ID_WOTC_TCOE_SPELL_SUMMON_ABERRATION" />
            <grant type="Spell" spellcasting="Psion_KTH" id="ID_WOTC_TCOE_SPELL_SUMMON_CELESTIAL" />
            <grant type="Spell" spellcasting="Psion_KTH" id="ID_WOTC_TCOE_SPELL_SUMMON_FIEND" />
        </rules>
    </element>

    <element name="Astral Swap" type="Class Feature" source="KibblesTasty Psion" id="ID_KIBBLESTASTY_PSION_TALENT_ASTRAL_SWAP">
        <supports>Psionic Talent, PsionicSynthesis</supports>
        <prerequisite>Psionic Synthesis, Projection Discipline, Transposition Discipline</prerequisite>
        <requirements>ID_KIBBLESTASTY_PSION_FEAT_PSIONIC_SYNTHESIS, ID_KIBBLESTASTY_PSION_DISCIPLINE_PROJECTION, ID_KIBBLESTASTY_PSION_DISCIPLINE_TRANSPOSITION</requirements>
        <description>
            <p>As a bonus action, you can Phase Rift to where your Astral Construct is; this movement counts as a Phase Rift, and you can apply modifiers to it as normal. Your Astral Construct is moved to where you started this movement along the Phase Rift; during the movement you can command your Astral Construct to attack a creature pases with its action.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description action="Bonus Action">As a bonus action, you can Phase Rift to where your Astral Construct is; this movement counts as a Phase Rift, and you can apply modifiers to it as normal. Your Astral Construct is moved to where you started this movement along the Phase Rift; during the movement you can command your Astral Construct to attack a creature pases with its action.</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>

    <element name="Reality Warper" type="Class Feature" source="KibblesTasty Psion" id="ID_KIBBLESTASTY_PSION_TALENT_REALITY_WARPER">
        <supports>Psionic Talent, PsionicSynthesis</supports>
        <prerequisite>Psionic Synthesis, Matter Made Real, Mental Image</prerequisite>
        <requirements>ID_KIBBLESTASTY_PSION_FEAT_PSIONIC_SYNTHESIS, ID_KIBBLESTASTY_PSION_TALENT_MATTER_MADE_REAL, ID_KIBBLESTASTY_PSION_TALENT_MENTAL_IMAGE</requirements>
        <description>
            <p>You can bring the illusions you make people see to life. When you are concentrating on an illusion spell, as a bonus action you can expend psi points during your turn you can bring aspects of the illusion into reality. For each psi point spent you can bring a 5-foot cube section of the illusion into reality until the start of your next turn, and it can have the following effects:</p>
            <ul>
                <li>If the effect would do damage, each 5-foot cube damage one target. That target must pass a Dexterity saving throw, or take damage equal to a number of d8 dice equal to the level of the spell.</li>
                <li>If the effect would stop a creature, they cannot move through it. If the effect would restrain a creature, the that creature must pass a Dexterity saving throw or become restrained until the start of your next turn.</li>
            </ul>
            <p class="indent">Each 5-foot cube can effect only one creature that is either within it or adjacent to it. The DM may allow grant it other effects as their discretion.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>You can bring the illusions you make people see to life. When you are concentrating on an illusion spell, as a bonus action you can expend psi points during your turn you can bring aspects of the illusion into reality. For each psi point spent you can bring a 5-foot cube section of the illusion into reality until the start of your next turn, and it can have the following effects:
            If the effect would do damage, each 5-foot cube damage one target. That target must pass a Dexterity saving throw, or take damage equal to a number of d8 dice equal to the level of the spell.
            If the effect would stop a creature, they cannot move through it. If the effect would restrain a creature, the that creature must pass a Dexterity saving throw or become restrained until the start of your next turn.
            Each 5-foot cube can effect only one creature that is either within it or adjacent to it. The DM may allow grant it other effects as their discretion.</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>

    <element name="Phantom Blade Barrage" type="Class Feature" source="KibblesTasty Psion" id="ID_KIBBLESTASTY_PSION_TALENT_PHANTOM_BLADE_BARRAGE">
        <supports>Psionic Talent, PsionicSynthesis</supports>
        <prerequisite>Psionic Synthesis, Projected Weaponry, Telekinetic Weapons</prerequisite>
        <requirements>ID_KIBBLESTASTY_PSION_FEAT_PSIONIC_SYNTHESIS, ID_KIBBLESTASTY_PSION_TALENT_PROJECTED_WEAPONRY, ID_KIBBLESTASTY_PSION_TALENT_TELEKINETIC_WEAPONS</requirements>
        <description>
            <p>You can create a weapon with Projected Weapon as part of making an attack with it using Telekinetic Weapons, allowing you to project as many weapons in this manner as you make attacks (no additional action required). When you use weapons created by Projected Weaponry as the projectiles for your Telekinetic Weapons, the range you can fling the weapons is doubled.</p>
            <p class="indent">Additionally, if you expend 6 psi points on the Whirling modifier of Telekinetic Weapons, you can cast blade barrier instead of cloud of daggers, generating much larger number of ethereal blades as part of the casting.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>You can create a weapon with Projected Weapon as part of making an attack with it using Telekinetic Weapons, allowing you to project as many weapons in this manner as you make attacks (no additional action required). When you use weapons created by Projected Weaponry as the projectiles for your Telekinetic Weapons, the range you can fling the weapons is doubled. Additionally, if you expend 6 psi points on the Whirling modifier of Telekinetic Weapons, you can cast blade barrier instead of cloud of daggers, generating much larger number of ethereal blades as part of the casting.</description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <grant type="Spell" spellcasting="Psion_KTH" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_BLADE_BARRIER" />
        </rules>
    </element>

    <element name="Parasitic Nightmare" type="Class Feature" source="KibblesTasty Psion" id="ID_KIBBLESTASTY_PSION_TALENT_PARASITIC_NIGHTMARE">
        <supports>Psionic Talent, PsionicSynthesis</supports>
        <prerequisite>Psionic Synthesis, Consumption Discipline, Telepathy Discipline</prerequisite>
        <requirements>ID_KIBBLESTASTY_PSION_FEAT_PSIONIC_SYNTHESIS, ID_KIBBLESTASTY_PSION_DISCIPLINE_CONSUMPTION, ID_KIBBLESTASTY_PSION_DISCIPLINE_TELEPATHY</requirements>
        <description>
            <p>You gain the ability to add Telepathic Intrusion modifiers to Mind Leech.</p>
            <p class="indent">Additionally, when you deal psychic damage to a creature that is frightened of you, you can render yourself invisible to that creature until the start of your next turn; you can immediately (no action required) roll an Intelligence (Stealth) check affecting only creatures you are invisible from as a result of this talent.</p>
            <p class="indent">If you are hidden from a creature that is of you frightened, when it moves, you can use your reaction to teleport to an unoccupied space within 5 feet of that creature (at the completion of their movement).</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>You gain the ability to add Telepathic Intrusion modifiers to Mind Leech. Additionally, when you deal psychic damage to a creature that is frightened of you, you can render yourself invisible to that creature until the start of your next turn; you can immediately (no action required) roll an Intelligence (Stealth) check affecting only creatures you are invisible from as a result of this talent. If you are hidden from a creature that is of you frightened, when it moves, you can use your reaction to teleport to an unoccupied space within 5 feet of that creature (at the completion of their movement).</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>

    <element name="The Void" type="Class Feature" source="KibblesTasty Psion" id="ID_KIBBLESTASTY_PSION_TALENT_THE_VOID">
        <supports>Psionic Talent, PsionicSynthesis</supports>
        <prerequisite>Psionic Synthesis, Consumption Discipline, Nullification Discipline</prerequisite>
        <requirements>ID_KIBBLESTASTY_PSION_FEAT_PSIONIC_SYNTHESIS, ID_KIBBLESTASTY_PSION_DISCIPLINE_CONSUMPTION, ID_KIBBLESTASTY_PSION_DISCIPLINE_NULLIFICATION</requirements>
        <description>
            <p>You devour all supernatural effects near you. Whenever a creature (including yourself) within 5 feet of you takes damage from magical source, you can expend 1 or more psi points to use your reaction to reduce the damage taken by 1d8 per psi point spent. You can divide this amount between multiple creatures within range if they take damage at the same time.</p>
            <p class="indent">Additionally, whenever you successfully cast counterspell, dispel magic, or remove curse, you regain hit points equal to the level of spell stopped or ended.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>Whenever a creature (including yourself) within 5 feet of you takes damage from magical source, you can expend 1 or more psi points to use your reaction to reduce the damage taken by 1d8 per psi point spent. You can divide this amount between multiple creatures within range if they take damage at the same time. Additionally, whenever you successfully cast counterspell, dispel magic, or remove curse, you regain hit points equal to the level of spell stopped or ended.</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>

    <element name="Element Eater" type="Class Feature" source="KibblesTasty Psion" id="ID_KIBBLESTASTY_PSION_TALENT_ELEMENT_EATER">
        <supports>Psionic Talent, PsionicSynthesis</supports>
        <prerequisite>Psionic Synthesis, Elemental Mind, Consumption Discipline</prerequisite>
        <requirements>ID_KIBBLESTASTY_PSION_FEAT_PSIONIC_SYNTHESIS, ID_KIBBLESTASTY_PSION_ARCHETYPE_ELEMENTAL, ID_KIBBLESTASTY_PSION_DISCIPLINE_CONSUMPTION</requirements>
        <description>
            <p>Your mind is merged with your elemental power, and it is life and sustainence for you, integrating with your powers of consumption, granting you the following benefits:</p>
            <ul>
                <li>When cast absorb elements the damage bonus can applied to your Mind Leech power as bonus psychic damage.</li>
                <li>When you a creature with resistance or immunity to Acid, Cold, Fire, Lightning, or Thunder damage fails a saving throw against your Mind Leech power, you gain resistance to the damage type it has resistance or immunity to (if the creature has multiple resistances or immunities to those damage types, you gain one of your choice).</li>
                <li>You can using the Living Power modifiers Forming or Reaching to turn Mind Leech into a melee or ranged spell attack, as per those modifiers; you cannot add any Modifier that requires the target to fail a saving throw when using it this way.</li>
            </ul>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>When cast absorb elements the damage bonus can applied to your Mind Leech power as bonus psychic damage. When you a creature with resistance or immunity to Acid, Cold, Fire, Lightning, or Thunder damage fails a saving throw against your Mind Leech power, you gain resistance to the damage type it has resistance or immunity to (if the creature has multiple resistances or immunities to those damage types, you gain one of your choice). You can using the Living Power modifiers Forming or Reaching to turn Mind Leech into a melee or ranged spell attack, as per those modifiers; you cannot add any Modifier that requires the target to fail a saving throw when using it this way.</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>
    
<p class="indent"></p>
</elements>